stirworld.com 2019-12-16

# Privacy Policy - STIRworld

This Privacy Policy applies to all STIR’s websites and sub-domains, its services and application software (“Services”) offered by STIR Design Private Limited or its subsidiaries or affiliated companies.

## 1\. Information we collect and how we use it

We may collect the following types of information:

(a) **Log information –** When you access our Services via a browser, application or other client our servers automatically record certain information. These server logs may include information such as your web request, your interaction with a service, Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser or your account etc... 

(b) **User communications –** When you send email or other communications to us, we may retain those communications in order to process your inquiries, respond to your requests and improve our services. When you send and receive SMS messages to or from one of our services that provides SMS functionality, we may collect and maintain information associated with those messages, such as the phone number, the wireless carrier associated with the phone number, the content of the message, and the date and time of the transaction. We may use your email address to communicate with you about our services. 

(c) **Affiliate STIR services on other sites –** We offer some of our services on or through other websites. Personal information that you provide to those sites may be sent to us in order to deliver the service. We process such information under this Privacy Policy. 

(d) **Third Party Applications –** We may make available third-party applications, such as gadgets or extensions, through its services. The information collected by us when you enable a third-party application is processed under this Privacy Policy. Information collected by the third-party application provider is governed by their privacy policies. 

(e) **Location data –** We may offer location-enabled services. If you use those services, we may receive information about your actual location (such as GPS signals sent by a mobile device) or information that can be used to approximate a location (such as a cell ID). 

(f) **Other sites –** This Privacy Policy applies to the Services referred to in this Privacy Policy only. We do not exercise control over the sites displayed as search results, sites that include links from within our various services. These other sites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you. 

## We may use the information we collect to:

(a) provide, maintain, protect, and improve our services (including advertising services) and develop new services; and protect our rights or property and / or those of our users.

(b) if we use this information in a manner different than the purpose for which it was collected, then we will ask for your consent prior to such use.

(c) we process personal information on our servers in India and in other countries. In some cases, we process personal information outside your own country.

## 2\. Information sharing

We only share personal information with other companies or individuals outside of STIR in the following limited circumstances:

(a) we have your consent. We require opt-in consent for the sharing of any sensitive personal information. We provide such information to our subsidiaries, affiliated companies or other trusted businesses or persons for the purpose of processing personal information on our behalf. We require that these parties agree to process such information based on our instructions and in compliance with this Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

(b) we have a good faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to (a) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request, (b) enforce applicable Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations thereof, (c) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, or (d) protect against harm to our rights, property or safety, our users or the public as required or permitted by law.

(c) in the event we are involved in a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of our assets, we will ensure the confidentiality of any personal information involved in such transactions and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

## 3\. Information security

We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. These include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, including appropriate encryption and physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where we store personal data.

We restrict access to personal information to our employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to process it on our behalf. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations.

## 4\. Accessing and updating personal information

When you use our Services, we make good faith efforts to provide you with access to your personal information and either to correct this data if it is inaccurate or to delete such data at your request if it is not otherwise required to be retained by law or for legitimate business purposes. We ask individual users to identify themselves and the information requested to be accessed, corrected or removed before processing such requests, and we may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup tapes), or for which access is not otherwise required. In any case where we provide information access and correction, we perform this service free of charge, except if doing so would require a disproportionate effort. Because of the way we maintain certain services, after you delete your information, residual copies may take a period before they are deleted from our active servers and may remain in our backup systems. 

## 5\. Enforcement and Changes to this Privacy Policy

We regularly review our compliance with this Privacy Policy. When we receive formal written complaints, it is our policy to contact the complaining user regarding his or her concerns. We will cooperate with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of personal data that cannot be resolved between us and an individual. 

Please note that this Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will not reduce your rights under this Privacy Policy without your explicit consent. We will post any Privacy Policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice (including, for certain services, email notification of Privacy Policy changes). We will also keep prior versions of this Privacy Policy in an archive for your review. 

## 6\. Cookies Policy

We employ the use of cookies. By accessing stirworld.com, you agreed to use cookies in agreement with the STIR Design Pvt. Ltd.’s Privacy Policy

Cookies are used by our website to enable the functionality of certain areas to make it easier for people visiting our website. Some of our affiliate/advertising partners may also use cookies. 

As is common practice with almost all professional websites this site uses cookies, which are tiny files that are downloaded to your computer, to improve your experience. This page describes what information they gather, how we use it and why we sometimes need to store these cookies. We will also share how you can prevent these cookies from being stored however this may downgrade or ‘break’ certain elements of the website’s functionality.

(a) We use cookies for a variety of reasons detailed below. Unfortunately, in most cases there are no industry standard options for disabling cookies without completely disabling the functionality and features they add to this site. It is recommended that you leave on all cookies if you are not sure whether you need them or not in case, they are used to provide a service that you use.

(b) You can prevent the setting of cookies by adjusting the settings on your browser (see your browser Help for how to do this). Be aware that disabling cookies will affect the functionality of this and many other websites that you visit. Disabling cookies will usually result in also disabling certain functionality and features of this site. Therefore, it is recommended that you do not disable cookies. 

(c) If you create an account with us then we will use cookies for the management of the signup process and general administration. These cookies will usually be deleted when you log out however in some cases they may remain afterwards to remember your site preferences when logged out.

(d) We use cookies when you are logged in so that we can remember this fact. This prevents you from having to log in every single time you visit a new page. These cookies are typically removed or cleared when you log out to ensure that you can only access restricted features and areas when logged in.

(e) This site offers newsletter or email subscription services and cookies may be used to remember if you are already registered and whether to show certain notifications which might only be valid to subscribed/unsubscribed users.

(f) From time to time we offer user surveys and questionnaires to provide you with interesting insights, helpful tools, or to understand our user base more accurately. These surveys may use cookies to remember who has already taken part in a survey or to provide you with accurate results after you change pages.

(g) When you submit data to through a form such as those found on contact pages or comment forms cookies may be set to remember your user details for future correspondence. 

(h) In order to provide you with a great experience on this site we provide the functionality to set your preferences for how this site runs when you use it. In order to remember your preferences we need to set cookies so that this information can be called whenever you interact with a page is affected by your preferences

## 7\. Third Party Cookies

(a) In some special cases we also use cookies provided by trusted third parties. The following section details which third party cookies you might encounter through this site.

(b) This site uses Google Analytics which is one of the most widespread and trusted analytics solutions on the web for helping us to understand how you use the site and ways that we can improve your experience. These cookies may track things such as how long you spend on the site and the pages that you visit so we can continue to produce engaging content.

(c) For more information on Google Analytics cookies, see the official Google Analytics page. The Google AdSense service we use to serve advertising uses a DoubleClick cookie to serve more relevant ads across the web and limit the number of times that a given ad is shown to you. For more information on Google AdSense see the official Google AdSense privacy FAQ.
